Register of the John M. Levinson Papers, 1954-1991
Hoover Institution Archives
John M. Levinson Papers,
1954-1991
84061
Levinson, John M., 1927-
30 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes, 14 envelopes, 1 album box, 1 phonotape cassette (18 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Speeches and writings, conference proceedings, reports, studies, memoranda, correspondence, pamphlets, hearing transcripts, serials, clippings, other printed matter, and photographs, relating to medical conditions in Vietnam and elsewhere in Indochina, private American medical and other relief assistance to Vietnam, and the medical effects of use of defoliants and herbicides in Vietnam during the Vietnamese War. Includes postage stamps issued by the governments of French Indochina, Cambodia, Laos, and North and South Vietnam, 1889-1974.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1984.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Postage-stamps--Indochina.; Indochina.; Cambodia.; Laos.; Vietnam.; Phonotapes.; Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975--Medical care.; Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975--Civilian relief.; Medical assistance, American--Vietnam.; Public health--Vietnam.; International relief.; Herbicides--War use.; Agent Orange.; United States--Foreign relations.; Aid for International Medicine.; Chemical warfare.; United States. Congress. Senate. Committee on the Judiciary. Subcommittee to Investigate Problems Connected with Refugees and Escapees.
Biographical Note
1927 August 17 Born, Atlantic City, New Jersey
1945-1947 Served in U.S. Navy
1949 B.S. Lafayette College, Easton, Pennsylvania
1953 M.D. Jefferson Medical College, Philadelphia
1963-1983 Made various trips to Vietnam, Laos, and Cambodia
1964 Lobbied for Volunteer Physicians for Viet Nam Program
1965 Founded Aid for International Medicine
1967 Became consultant to Edward M. Kennedy's U.S. Senate Subcommittee to Investigate Problems Connected with Refugees and Escapees
1967-1973 Participated in Subcommittee study missions to Vietnam
1967-1976 Served on CARE-MEDICO board of directors
1978 Became consultant to U.S. Veterans Administration
Associate Professor of Obstetrics and Gynecology at Jefferson Medical College, Philadelphia
Series Description
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1963-1985 (Box 1)
  Includes clippings and scrapbook arranged by physical format.
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1963-1986 (Box 1, 26)
  Includes letters and enclosures (clippings and reports), and greeting cards arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1964-1985 (Box 1, 26)
  Includes notes and typewritten copies of speeches, synopsis of proposed book, and printed articles arranged chronologically by date of publication or writing.
- SUBJECT FILE, 1954-1985 (Box 2-21, 26-30)
  Includes clippings, printed articles pamphlets, monographs, serials, reports, maps, memoranda, correspondence, hearing transcripts, conference proceedings and papers, and travel itineraries arranged alphabetically by subject.
- POSTAGE STAMPS, 1889-1979 (Box 21-24)
  Includes stamps, albums, and catalogs arranged alphabetically by name of country.
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1889-1967 (Box 25, 31)
  Includes postage stamps, scrapbooks and printed material arranged by physical format.
- PHONOTAPE CASSETTE, 1983 (Cassette Cabinet)
  Single cassette.
- AUDIO-VISUAL, 1963-1983 (10.A-V, 8M.02)
  Includes photographs and postcards, arranged chronologically.
Container List
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1963-1985
  - General, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1966-1985 (Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1967 (Folder 3)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1963-1986
  - General, 1965-1986? (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Unidentified, 1963 (Folder 5)
  - Abrams, George, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Ahlgren, Regina, 1967 (Folder 2)
  - American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Medical Association, 1966 (Folder 7)
  - Australia. Royal Commission on the Use and Effects of Chemical Agents on Australian Personnel in Vietnam, 1984 (Folder 8)
  - Ball, Neil, 1982 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Banganz, Herbert M., 1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bennett, Lansing H., 1983 (Folder 10)
  - Biden, Joseph R., Jr., 1975 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Bisanti, Luigi, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Boggs, J. Caleb, 1965-1972 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Bundy, McGeorge, 1965 (Folder 6)
  - CARE-MEDICO, 1964-1975 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Carper, Thomas R., 1982-1984 (Folder 13)
  - China Medical Board of New York, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Codario, Ronald A., 1983 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - College of Physicians of Philadelphia, 1985 (Folder 15)
  - Constable, John D., 1983 (Folder 16)
  - Cooper, Chester L., 1965 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Cooperman, Edward L., 1982 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Cosgrove, George, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Davidson, Henry, 1973 (Folder 10)
  - Du Pont, Kathie (Mrs. Reynolds), 1965 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Du Pont, Pierre S., 1971 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Edwards, Don, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Erben, John J., 1969 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Eudy, Richard, 1969 (Folder 13)
  - Golin, Edwin, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Haney, Robert R., 1983 (Folder 21)
  - Hercules Incorporated, 1982 (Folder 22)
  - Hoang Dinh Cau, 1982-1983 (Folder 23)
  - Hoover, Norman W., 1972 (Folder 24)
  - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1965-1971 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Ives, Ginny, 1980 (Folder 15)
  - Kay, Keith, 1974-1975 (Folder 16)
  - Le Cao Dai, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Le Van Hoa, n.d. (Folder 26)
  - Legnitto, Jan, 1982 (Folder 27)
  - Lesaca, R. M., 1983 (Folder 28)
  - Levinson, Elizabeth, 1963-1967 (Folder 29)
  - Levinson, John, Jr., n.d. (Folder 30)
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - McCarthy, Frank, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - McClanahan, Roger B., n.d. (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - McCloskey, Paul N., 1971-1972 (Folder 19)
  - McDowell, Harris, Jr., 1963-1965 (Folder 20)
  - McMichael, Joan K., 1974 (Folder 21)
  - Megellas, James, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Newell, Frank, 1982 (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Newton, Roger, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Nguyen Duong Quang, 1982 (Folder 34)
  - Nguyen Van Khoi, 1975 (Folder 35)
  - Paul, Anthony, 1982-1983 (Folder 36)
  - Planned Parenthood World Population, 1965 (Folder 37)
  - Puglisi, Paulo, 1982 (Folder 38)
  - Roth, William V., Jr., 1966-1982 (Folder 39)
  - Schecter, Arnold, 1985 (Folder 40)
  - Silver, Stephen, 1983 (Folder 41)
  - TeLinde, Richard W., 1964-1966 (Folder 42)
  - Van Tiggelen, Cees J. M., 1983 (Folder 43)
  - United States Agency for International Development, 1965-1973 (Folder 44)
  - United States. Marine Corps, 1969 (Folder 45)
  - United States Operations Mission to Vietnam, 1966 (Folder 46)
  - Vastyan, E. A., 1971 (Folder 47)
  - Walker, Susan, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Westing, Arthur H., 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Williams, I. M. G., 1974 (Box 26, Folder 24)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1964-1985
  - "MEDICO Report on Global Gynecology," 1963 December. Mimeographed copy (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - "MEDICO Report on Global Gynecology," 1964 November-December. Mimeographed copy (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - "Medicine in South Vietnam," Journal of the American Medical Associaton, 1965 May 31. Printed copy (Folder 50)
  - Speech, Statement to the U.S. Senate Subcommittee on Foreign Relations, 1966 April 27. Mimeographed copy (Folder 51)
  - Speech, Statement to the U.S. Senate Judiciary Subcommittee on Refugees and Escapees, 1967 October 9. Typewritten copy with addendum explaining photographs (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - "Statement on South Vietnam," October 27, 1971. Presented to Paul McCloskey. Includes critique by D. G. MacDonald, USAID (Folder 27)
  - "A Companion of Health Care in Indochina," Speech, 1973. Handwritten transcript (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - "North Vietnam Maternal Care Advances Vastly Despite War," Ob. Gyn. News, 1973 November 15. Reprint (Folder 53)
  - "North Vietnam's Institutes Offer Depth in Specialties," Ob. Gyn. News, 1973 December 1. Reprint (Folder 54)
  - "Obstetrics and Gynecology in the Democratic Republic of Vietnam (North Vietnam)," 1973-1974? Typewritten copy (Box 26, Folder 28)
  - "Traditional Medicine in the Democratic Republic of North Vietnam," The American Journal of Chinese Medicine, vol. 2, no. 2, 1974. Reprint (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - "Challenges and Opportunities," Piego Newsletter, 1975 February. Typewritten and printed copies (Box 26, Folder 29)
  - Letter to the Editor, Delaware Medical Journal, 1975 March. Printed copy (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - "Agent Orange," Speech, Veterans Administration, 1982. Handwritten notes (Folder 57)
  - "Agent Orange - A Perspective on Responsibility," Speech, Veterans Administration Advisory Committee on Health- Related Effects of Herbicides, 1983 December 6. Typewritten copy (Box 26, Folder 30)
  - "Follow Up Questions and Remarks Including Observations in Australia and New Zealand," Speech, Veterans Administration Advisory Committee on Health-Related Effects of Herbicides, 1984 June 5 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - "Country 77," with David Bailey, 1985
    - Correspondence and notes (Folder 59)
    - Typewritten synopsis of chapters. Two drafts (Folder 60)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1954-1985
  - Agent Orange
    - General
      - General
        - 1971-1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
        - 1983-1987 (Folder 2)
      - Clippings, 1972-1984 (Folder 3)
      - Notes
        - 1982-1983 (Folder 4)
        - 1984 (Folder 5)
      - Reports
        - 1964-1980 (Folder 6)
        - 1981. Includes a student research report entitled "Agent Orange at the Crossroads of Science and Social Concern," by Major Alvin L. Young, USAF (Folder 7)
        - 1984. Includes a report entitled "'Dioxin,' A perspective from the Medical point of View," by George Lumb, M.D. (Folder 8)
        - Testimony, 1980-1983. Includes testimony before the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs, Subcommittee on Medical Facilities and Benefits, by Samuel S. Epstein, 1980 July 22 (Folder 9)
    - Agent Orange Victims International, 1980 (Folder 10)
    - American Chemical Society, 1983. Includes a report entitled "Chlorinated dioxins as herbicide contaminants" (Folder 11)
    - American Medical Association (Folder 12)
      - Beljan, John R., "Statement of the American Medical Association to the Subcommittee on Compensation, Pension and Insurance, Committee on Veterans' Affairs, U.S. House of Representatives," 1983 July 12
      - Beljan, John R. et al., "The Health Effects of 'Agent Orange' and Polychlorinated Dioxin Contaminants: An Update, 1984," 1984
    - Australia. Department of Veterans' Affairs, 1982-1983 (Folder 13)
    - Australia. Parliament. Relates to veterans' claims
      - 1980-1982 (Folder 14)
      - 1981-1983 (Folder 15)
    - Australia. Repatriation Review Tribunal, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Australia. Royal Commission, 1981-1984 (Folder 2)
    - Australian Veterans Health Studies, 1983. A report to the Minister for Veterans' Affairs entitled Case-Control Study of Congenital Anomalies and Vietnam Service (Birth Defects Study) (Folder 3)
    - Cabinet Council on Human Resources. Agent Orange Working Group, 1981-1982 (Folder 4)
    - Council on Scientific Affairs, 1981-1982. Includes a technical report entitled "The Health Effects of 'Agent Orange' and Polychlorinated Dioxin Contaminants" (Folder 5)
    - Delaware, State of. House of Representatives, 1983 (Folder 6)
    - Dow Chemical Company, 1980-1983 (Folder 7)
    - Dwyer, James H. (Folder 8)
      - "Health Problems of U.S. Military Veterans and Possible Exposure to Phenoxy Acid Herbicides in Vietnam: Partial Coding and Statistical Analysis of the Citizen Soldier Health Questionnaire (CSHQ)," 1981
      - "Summary of Proceedings of a Conference on Herbicide Exposure and Reproductive Epidemiology in Viet Nam," 1982
    - Foundation for Advancement in Science & Education, 1984. Includes printed matter on dioxin (Folder 9)
    - Hercules Incorporated, 1984. Includes speech by vice-president S. Maynard Turk (Folder 10)
    - New Jersey, State of. Agent Orange Commission, 1984-1985. Includes a report entitled "The Measurement of Blood Dioxin Levels in Vietnam Veterans Who Were Heavily Exposed to Agent Orange during the War: A Pilot Project," draft copy (Folder 11)
    - New York, State of. Temporary Commission on Dioxin Exposure, 1982 (Folder 12)
    - Ohio Veterans Agent Orange Program, n.d. (Folder 13)
    - United States. Air Force (Folder 14)
      - Young, Alvin L. et al, The Toxicology, Environmental Fate, and Human Risk of Herbicide Orange and its Associated Dioxin, 1978 October
      - Chesney, Major General Murphy A., "Presentation to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs, Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations," 1982 September 15
      - "An Epidemiologic Investigation of Health Effects in Air Force Personnel Following Exposure to Herbicides," 1983 June 30
    - United States. Congress, 1984. Includes material on H.R. 1961 (Folder 15)
    - United States. General Accounting Office, 1979. A report entitled "U.S. Ground Troops in South Vietnam Were in Areas Sprayed with Herbicide Orange" (Folder 16)
    - Van Tiggelen, Cees J. M., 1983-1984. Includes reports and published articles (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Veterans Administration
      - General
        - General, 1982-1985 (Folder 2)
        - Correspondence
          - 1983 (Folder 3)
          - 1983-1985 (Folder 4)
      - Advisory Committee on Health-Related Effects of Herbicides
        - General, 1983-1984 (Folder 5)
        - Meetings, 1983-1985. Includes agendas, notes, and membership lists (Folder 6)
        - Transcripts of Proceedings
          - 1983 February 24 (Folder 7)
          - 1983 May 20 (Folder 8)
          - 1983 September 1
          - 1983 December 6 (Folder 9)
          - 1984 March 6
          - 1984 June 5 (Folder 10)
          - 1984 September 12 (Box 5, Folder 1)
          - 1984 December (Folder 2)
          - 1985 March 26 (Folder 3)
          - 1985 October 22 (Box 26, Folder 31)
          - 1986 June 12 (Folder 32)
          - 1986 October 21 (Folder 33)
      - "Agent Orange Review," 1982-1984 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Custis, Donald L., 1982-1983. Testimony before the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs, Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations (Folder 5)
      - Hood, Ronald D., Ph.D., Cacodylic Acid: Agricultural Uses, Biologic Effects, and Environmental Fate, 1985 December (Box 26, Folder 34)
      - Lavy, T. L., Ph.D., Human Exposure to Phenoxy Herbicides, 1987 May (Folder 35)
      - Review of Literature on Herbicides, Including Phenoxy Herbicides and Associated Dioxins, 1981-1985
        - Synopsis (Box 5, Folder 6)
        - Volumes I-III (Folder 7)
        - Volumes IV-V (Box 6, Folder 1)
        - Volumes VII-VIII (Box 26, Folder 36)
        - Volumes IX-X (Folder 37)
      - Synopsis of Scientific Literature on Phenoxy Herbicides and Associated Dioxins, 1985 (Folder 38)
        - No. 1 (Volumes I-IV)
        - No. 2 (Volumes V-VI)
        - No. 3 (Volumes VII-VIII)
        - No. 4 (Volumes IX-X)
    - Vietnam Combat Veterans Coalition, 1983-1984. Includes newsletter "Orange Dispatch" (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Vietnam Veterans of America, 1979-1984 (Folder 3)
    - Vietnam Veterans Association of Australia
      - General, 1981-1983 (Folder 4)
      - "Debrief," 1982-1984 (Folder 5)
  - Amerasians
    - General. Includes typewritten manuscript addressing the question of Amerasian children and the U.S. Government's responsibilities, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, 1982 (Folder 2)
    - Correspondence
      - Unidentified, 1979-1983 (Folder 3)
      - Colin, Dan, 1982 (Folder 4)
      - Dang Thi Ngoc Co, 1982 (Folder 5)
      - Doan Thi Quang, 1982 (Folder 6)
      - Hastings, Terry (Mrs.), 1982 (Folder 7)
      - Kenney, Frederic, 1980-1983 (Folder 8)
      - Leung, Lena, 1983 (Folder 9)
      - May, William F., 1982 (Folder 10)
      - Nguyen Ngoc Bich Thuy, 1983 (Folder 11)
      - Nguyen Ngoc Tai, 1982 (Folder 12)
      - Nguyen Thi Loan, 1983 (Folder 13)
      - Nguyen Thi Loan, n.d. (Folder 14)
      - Nguyen Thi Ly, 1982-1985 (Folder 15)
      - Pearl S. Buck Foundation, 1982 (Folder 16)
      - Thuong Li Mai Thanh, 1983 (Folder 17)
      - Tran Thi Dien Minh, 1983 (Folder 18)
      - Tuyet Mai, 1983 (Folder 19)
    - Reports. United States Congressional Record, proceedings and debates of the 97th Congress, second session, 1982 September 28. Includes statements on immigration and Amerasian children. Printed copy (Folder 20)
  - Chemical Warfare
    - General. Includes articles, clippings, and correspondence
      - 1965-1982 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - 1983-1985 (Folder 7)
    - Goldstein, Jonathan, 1982-1984. Includes a report entitled "Vietnam Research on Campus: The Summit/Spicerak Controversy at the University of Pennsylvania, 1965-1967" (Folder 8)
    - International Symposium on the Long-Term Ecological and Human Consequences of Chemical Warfare in Viet Nam, Ho Chi Minh City, 1983 January 13-20
      - General, 1982-1983 (Folder 9)
      - Abstracts of papers, alphabetical by author (Folder 10)
      - Agenda (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Memoranda, 1982-1983 (Folder 2)
      - Papers, alphabetical by author (Folder 3-6)
      - Proceedings
        - Typescript (Folder 7)
        - Printed, French
          - Volumes 1-2 (Folder 8)
          - Volume 3 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Reports (Folder 2)
    - United States. Secretary of State, 1982. A report to Congress entitled Chemical Warfare in Southeast Asia and Afghanistan (Folder 3)
    - Vietnam Courier, Hanoi (Folder 4)
      - U.S. Chemical Warfare and its Consequences, 1980
      - Herbicides and Defoliants in War: The Long-term Effects on Man and Nature, 1983
  - Foreign Aid to Vietnam
    - General, 1966-1968 (Folder 5)
    - CARE-Vietnam, 1967-1968 (Folder 6)
    - Indochina Aid and Friendship, 1982-1984 (Folder 7)
    - Indochina Mobil Education Project, 1973. Includes a monograph entitled Hostages of War: Saigon's Political Prisoners (Folder 8)
    - International Voluntary Services, Inc., 1966 (Folder 9)
    - United States Agency for International Development
      - General, 1967-1971. Includes correspondence with Senator Edward M. Kennedy and a directive on treatment of civilian war casualties (Folder 10)
      - Newsletter, 1965-1967 (Folder 11)
      - Newspaper, 1965 (Folder 12)
      - Orientation Material, n.d. (Folder 13)
      - Printed Matter. Relates to Vietnamese government administration
        - 1963 (Box 9, Folder 1-6)
        - 1964-1971 (Folder 7)
      - Speech. "The Third Face of War" excerpt from President Johnson's address to the Association of American Editorial Cartoonists at the White House, 1965 May 13. Printed copy (Box 27, Folder 21)
      - Transcript, press conference by Director D. G. MacDonald, 1968 December 12 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - United States Committee for Scientific Cooperation with Viet Nam, 1981-1984 (Folder 9)
    - United States Operations Mission to Vietnam, 1964-1965. Includes a monograph entitled The Police and Resources Control in Counter-Insurgency (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Vietnam. Ministry of National Planning and Development, 1971 (Folder 2)
  - Kampuchea
    - General, 1963. Includes typescript of Prince Sihanouk's address to the press, 1963 November 22 (Folder 3)
    - Clippings, 1967-1980 (Folder 4)
    - Notes (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - Printed Matter
      - 1970. A staff report prepared for the Senate Committee on Foreign Relations (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - 1979. Includes material published by the Foreign Languages Publishing House, Hanoi (Folder 6)
      - 1979. United States Department of State, Fact Sheet - Cambodia/Kampuchea Typewritten copy (Box 27, Folder 23)
      - 1980. International Rescue Committee, Inc. Includes information pamphlet on the condition of the Cambodian refugees (Folder 24)
      - 1980. News pamphlet, Clearing House News, published by Cambodia Refugee Health Clearing House. Printed copy (Folder 25)
      - 1980. News pamphlet, Franciscan Capsule, published by St. Francis Hospital, Wilmington, Delaware. Printed copy (Folder 26)
      - 1980-1983. Includes material published by the Vietnam Courier, Hanoi (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Reports
      - 1970 (Folder 8)
      - 1974. David M. French, "Cambodian Health Care System" (Folder 9)
      - 1980. "Cambodia: A Land of Unending Strife," Massachusetts General Hospital News, May. Printed copy (Box 27, Folder 27)
      - 1980. "The Second Holocaust," Journal of the American Medical Association, June 6. Printed copy (Folder 28)
      - 1980. "Medical Care of Cambodian Refugees." Journal of the American Medical Association, March 14. Printed copy (Folder 29)
  - Laos
    - 1973 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - 1982-1983 (Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1973-1974
      - Bronsther, Burton, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 30)
      - Ford Foundation, 1974 (Folder 31)
      - French, David M., 1973-1974 (Folder 32)
      - Lao Planning Association, 1974 (Folder 33)
      - Phing Norindr, 1974 (Folder 34)
      - United States Agency for International Development, 1974 (Folder 35)
    - Reports
      - "The Refugee Problem in Laos," presented by Dr. John Levinson and Dr. Nevin Scrimshaw, 1973 March. Typewritten copy (Folder 36)
      - "Laos," 1974 February. Typewritten copy (Folder 37)
  - Medical Assistance to Southeast Asia
    - General
      - General. Includes information on hospital facilities and civilian war casualties
        - 1963-1967 (Box 11, Folder 1)
        - 1968-1970 (Folder 2)
      - Clippings
        - 1964-1965 (Folder 3)
        - 1966 (Folder 4)
        - 1967 (Folder 5)
        - 1968-1971 (Folder 6)
        - 1974-1982 (Box 27, Folder 38)
      - Correspondence, 1964-1985
        - General, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 7)
        - "An Lac" Orphanage, 1971-1973 (Box 27, Folder 39)
        - Cervelli, Denise R., 1979-1980 (Folder 40)
        - Danh Van Tung, 1966-1975 (Folder 41)
        - Diem, Bui, 1967 (Folder 42)
        - First Regional Assistance Command, 1972-1973 (Folder 43)
        - Kennedy, Edward, 1967-1982 (Folder 44)
        - Kontum Hospital Fund, 1972 (Folder 45)
        - Lily Endowment, 1974 (Folder 46)
        - Medical Society of Delaware, 1979 (Folder 47)
        - Nguyen, LeAnne, 1972 (Folder 48)
        - Nguyen, Van Dong, 1978-1982 (Folder 49)
        - Nguyen, Van Khoi, 1974-1975 (Folder 50)
        - Phan Ngoc Hai, 1979-1981 (Folder 51)
        - Project Vietnam, 1965 (Folder 52)
        - Scrimshaw, Nevin, 1982 (Folder 53)
        - Tam Bui Duy, 1975 (Folder 54)
        - Thieme, Earl L., n.d. (Folder 55)
        - United States Committee for Scientific Cooperation with Vietnam, 1980-1985 (Folder 56)
        - United States Operations Mission to Vietnam, 1965 (Folder 57)
        - Vietnam Committee for Solidarity and Friendship with the People of all Countries, 1973-1979 (Folder 58)
      - Notes. Includes information on hospitals visited by John M. Levinson (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Printed Matter. Includes articles published in medical journals
        - Undated (Folder 9)
        - 1965-1967 (Folder 10)